Ladies and gentlemen, good evening and a
very warm welcome to the ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited Q4 and
FY2026 earnings conference call.
From the senior management, we have with
us today Mr. Sanjeev Mantri, MD and CEO
of the company,
Mr. Gopal Balachandran, CFO,
Mr. Anand Singhi, Chief Retail and
Government,
Mr. Girish Nayak, Chief Enterprise AI
and Technology,
Mr. Sandeep Bakhshi, Chief Corporate
Solutions, International and
Bancassurance,
Mr. Gaurav Arora,
Chief Commercial Lines and Motor,
Underwriting and Claims,
and Mr. Girish Segal, Chief Health, UW
and Claims, Customer Service and
Operations.
Please note
that any statements or comments made in
today's call that may look like
forward-looking statements are based on
information presently available to the
management and do not constitute an
indication of any future performance as
the future involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from current views
being expressed.
As a reminder, all participants' lines
will be in the listen-only mode and
there will be an opportunity for you to
ask questions after the presentation
concludes.
Should you need assistance during this
conference,
please signal an operator by pressing
star then zero on your touch-tone phone.
Please note that this conference is
being recorded.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjeev Mantri, MD and CEO, ICICI
Lombard General Insurance Limited.
Thank you and over to you, sir.
Thank you.
Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call of ICICI Lombard for quarter four
and financial year 2026.
I would like to commence with an
overview of the economy and industry
trends which have shaped the operating
environment over past few months.
Coupled with insights on our company's
performance and our key initiatives.
Following that, our CFO, Gopal
Balachandran, will take you through the
company's financial performance for
quarter 4 and financial year 2026.
The quarter gone by has been an eventful
one.
For the first 2 months, the Indian
economy exhibited continued momentum of
growth from the previous quarter,
whereas the month of March 2026 has seen
has been unprecedented in terms of the
geopolitical challenges.
The ongoing conflict in West Asia has
heightened global economic uncertainty,
leading to volatility in energy prices
and financial markets.
These external risks could have some
spillover effects on the Indian economy,
warranting a measured and watchful
approach.
That being said, India's macroeconomic
fundamentals today are considerably
strong and more resilient than in
previous periods of global stress.
This provides a degree of comfort in our
ability to absorb external shocks,
although we remain mindful of evolving
global conditions.
Let me now dwell upon the ensuing
quarter and the year gone by.
Retail sales of private cars,
two-wheelers, and tractors remained
positive for the year.
In accordance with the data reported by
Vahan for financial year 2026, the sales
growth of private car and two-wheelers
stood at healthy 11.9% and 13.2%
respectively.
Pertinently, for H2 2026,
the sales growth of private car and
two-wheelers stood at 17.8 and 21.5 as
against 4.6 and 3.2 respectively in H1
2026 led by GST rationalization.
This continued momentum is also seen in
quarter 4 2026, wherein the growth of
private car and two-wheeler stood at a
healthy 16.3 and 24.7% respectively.
Also noteworthy was the fact that
two-wheeler sales surpassed surpassed
their pre-COVID peak and were at a
decadal high.
Even the sales of commercial vehicle,
this is the data reported by Vahan, have
witnessed a growth of 20.2% in H2, 2026
versus 14.4.9%
for H1 2026 and a full year growth of
12.9%.
Given the early trends of numbers
reported by certain banks, credit growth
is expected to be in double digits for
quarter 4, 2026 with broad-based
expansion across segments. Also vehicle
vehicle financing continued to be an
important contributor to credit growth,
broadly in line with the trends observed
in retail automobile sales.
We believe that the above factors
augment well for the industry in time to
come.
Moving to the regulatory update, you may
be aware that IRDA has mandated insurers
to prepare and present their financial
statements in accordance with the
applicable India. Effective 1st April,
2026. We view We view this as a positive
step as the enhanced disclosure
requirements under India
framework will meaningfully improve
transparency and align the reporting
standards of Indian insurers with global
practices.
While the regulator requires insurers to
provide the reporting as per both India
and Indian GAAP for 2027 and 2028, it is
provided the insurer the option of
seeking forbearance to transitioning the
statutory accounting to India for the
first year.
We have examined the option provided by
the authority and we believe it would be
appropriate to seek the forbearance in
order to ensure that the transition is
executed in a calibrated and
operationally robust manner.
Another important initiative announced
by the authority is the public insurance
registry, which is expected to become a
key pillar of India's digital public
infrastructure.
As the framework evolves, PIR has the
potential to support industry growth by
improving penetration, driving
efficiencies, elevating customer
service, and also enabling better risk
selection across ecosystem. We believe
that over time it will also
enhance transparency, strengthen trust,
and create enduring benefit for the
policy holder, insurer, and the broader
financial system.
Let me now dwell upon the industry
performance for the year ended March
31st, 2026.
The general insurance industry reported
a GDPI growth of 9.2% for 2026.
Excluding crop and market linked
segment, the gross growth stood at 13.3%
for 2026.
Speaking of the specific segments within
the industry,
the commercial segment reported a growth
of 12.2%
for 2026.
However, if one was to break down this
growth into H1 and H2, the growth was
14.2 and 9.6% respectively.
As one observes,
the business witnessed elevated level of
competitive intensity and pricing
pressure, especially in the fire segment
in the second half of the year, leading
to muted growth.
The renewal of April 1st, 2026 also are
being reported at a discount to the
previous year, reflecting that this
trend is likely to continue for quarter
1, 2027 as well.
On the positive side, however, we also
would like to mention that the
the reinsurance renewals for financial
year 2027 have been solved.
The motor segment
growth for the industry stood at 9.2%
for financial year 2026. With the
momentum experienced post the GST
rationalization, the second half of the
year has witnessed improved growth
levels of 10.5 vis-a-vis the first half
which stood at 7.6%.
The health segment, including mark
health, grew by 15.4% for 2026, which
makes it the fastest growing segment for
last 5 years for from financial year
2022 to 2026.
Within this, the group health line of
business grew at 12.8% for 2026, whereas
the retail health grew growth stood at
19.9% for 2026.
Speaking on the underwriting performance
of the industry, overall the combined
ratio of the industry deteriorated from
113.2%
in 9 months financial year 2025 to 119.3
in 9 months 2026. The overall combined
ratio for private players remained
relatively flattish for from 111.2%
for the period 9 months 2025 to 111.5%
for the period 9 months 2026. Due to
pricing pressure, combined ratio for the
motor line of business continued to
remain elevated at 128.1%
for 9 months 2026 vis-a-vis 123.8% for
the period ended 9 months 2025.
I will now proceed to present our
company's performance across key
business segments for 2026. The company
reported a growth of 7% in gross
domestic premium income for 2026
compared to the industry growth of 9.2%
for the same period.
ICICI Lombard achieved a growth of 18.2%
and 15.7% in quarter 4 and S2 2026
respectively against an industry growth
of 10.9 and 11.2% over the same period.
However, excluding the crop and market
segment, the company recorded a growth
of 10.2%
and for financial year 2026 where the
industry grew at 13.3% for the same
period.
In the commercial line segment, our
growth stood at 5.4% for financial year
2026 as against compared to industry
growth of 12.2% for 2026.
During H1 2026, our growth in commercial
line stood at 6.5%
versus industry growth of 14.2%.
Whereas for H2 2026, the growth level
stood at 3.8%
percent versus industry growth of 9.6%.
Amidst Amidst competitive pressure, we
continue to drive profitable growth
through prudent underwriting and
judicious risk selection through our
multi-channel distribution. We continue
to maintain leadership position in
liability and marine cargo line of
business for financial year 2026.
In motor segment, our growth stood at
7.6% for financial year 2026 as against
industry growth of 9.2% for the same
period. In H1 of 2026, we grew at 2.2%
in the motor segment versus industry
growth which grew at 7.6%.
However, H2 of 2026, we exceeded the
growth level of industry by 1 and 1/2%
in motor, that is 12% versus the
industry growth of 10.5%.
This momentum was evident in quarter
four of financial year 2026 where we
achieved a growth of 15% with the while
the industry grew at 10%.
Our portfolio mix for private car,
two-wheeler and combined and commercial
vehicle stood at 52.8, 25.4
and 21.8% respectively for financial
year 2026.
In the health segment for 2026, we grew
by 20% as against the industry growth of
15.4%
on a Y by Y basis.
For quarter 4 2026, the growth stood at
a robust 38.2%
as against the industry growth of 20.5%.
Our retail health business
continued to demonstrate strong growth
of 51.1%
for 2026, significantly outpacing the
industry growth of 19.9% in the same
period.
Consequently, our market share has
improved from 3.3% in financial year
2025 to 4.1% in financial year 2026.
For the year, the company has seen a 2x
growth in the new retail health
indemnity business sold compared to the
previous year.
Our share of long-term premiums in new
business for retail health stands at
42.1%
for financial year 2021, up from 28.5%
for financial year 2025.
This performance has been driven by our
ongoing product innovation and sustained
investment in strengthening our retail
health health distribution franchise our
retail health
distribution franchise.
For the overall group health portfolio,
portfolio, we continue to maintain a
disciplined approach with a focus on
managing the book effectively. The group
health segment recorded a growth of 11%
for financial year 2026 over 2025
with a market share being 8.7% for
financial year 2026.
We have kept a focus on augmenting cash
flows through underlying long-term
business in various line of business.
Our advanced premium in motor insurance
has increased by over 15% in financial
2026 vis-a-vis financial year 2025.
Our market share in advance premium,
excluding motor share, stands at 12.5%
for financial year 2026, up from 9.6%
for financial year 2025.
Our disciplined focus on profitable
growth has helped us deliver consistent
outcome over time. With market
fluctuations may impact performance in
individual quarters, our track record
reflects our ability to navigate cycles
and deliver value over the long term.
If we analyze the 10-year time horizon
from financial year 2020 60 2016 to
2025, it is pertinent to note that the
company's average combined ratio stood
at 102.9%
reflecting sustained underwriting
discipline across various market
conditions. This would compare favorably
favorably with the industry average of
115.3%
over the same period.
Furthermore, our investment performance
has also remained strong.
Over the same 10-year
10-year horizon, we delivered a robust
average realized yield of 8.7% supported
by prudent asset allocation and
effective capital management over
multiple cycles. This in turn has
translated into an healthy average
return on equity of 19.1%
over the 10-year period,
which would compare favorably against
the industry average ROE of 4%.
Reinforcing the strength and resilience
of our overall business model and
consistency of our execution.
Our one and one team philosophy
continues to foster collaboration and
operational excellence,
enabling a unified approach across the
organization.
As a part of this philosophy, we'll now
apprise you of certain key initiatives.
First, I would like to highlight a
strategic capability we have built
in-house, one that materially
strengthens our execution engine. We
call it IL 1Force.
IL 1Force is an enterprise productivity
platform, which has been in operation
for over a year and is used by over
10,000 sales employees.
It is on track to become the single
operating platform for all our 15,000
employees across the organization.
IL 1Force integrates work execution,
performance management, collaboration,
and recognition into a single platform,
simplifying operations, reinforcing
execution discipline, and driving
accountability with real-time
enterprise-wide visibility.
The platform enables structured partner
engagement, task management, and
real-time performance analytics across
the partner life cycle.
Its renewal capability has improved
conversion by 5% while enhanced
engagement with while
enhanced engagement has doubled partner
participation and expanded market reach.
Notably, in health indemnity, improved
engagement led to a 2x increase in agent
activation and a doubling of new retail
business.
Our IL Take Care app, a one-stop
solution for insurance and wellness
needs, achieved 21 million downloads as
of 31st March 2026, reflecting the
growing customer engagement and digital
adoption. The GWP earned from the IL
Take Care app during the period 2026 was
501 5170 million vis-à-vis the
corresponding premium earning for 2025,
which stood at 2237
.2 million.
From a claim intimation perspective, 67%
of the customers now intimate their
health reimbursement claims through the
app, while 82% of the claim intimation
of our travel product, Trip Secure Plus,
went through IL Take Care app.
We'll continue to focus on improving the
service experience of our customers with
a single simplified interface for their
insurance requirements.
We continue to improve our efficiency
level in motor claims, too.
Our preferred partner network service
75.5%
of our non-OEM claims for quarter 4
2026, respectively, up from 74.1%
for quarter 4 2025. For 9 months, we
recorded an NPS of 69 for motor claims.
In the retail segment, 98.8%
of our total claims were paid within 30
days for financial year 2026. For the 9
months 2026, on an account basis, the
number stood at 99.9%
with the corresponding number for the
industry being at 82.1%.
For 9 months 2026, we recorded an NPS
of 73 for health claims, demonstrating
strong satisfaction level, and
reinforcing our position as a
customer-centric organization.
I have further strengthened our
on-ground claim supports for our health
customers, and our customer coverage
improving by 25% over the previous year.
As a part of the feedback, 95% of our
customers surveyed rated their
experience as exemplary, highlighting
the support provided during claims
processing and assistance with hospital
coordination. This reaffirms our focus
on best-in-class service to our
customers during the moment that truly
matters.
The 1 app 1 call center initiative
continues to deliver strong momentum in
the company's transition toward a
digital-first, do-it-yourself service
model. In March 2026, more than 5 lakh
service engagements, 69% of the total
service engagements were executed
digitally.
Our differentiated service initiatives,
which we spoke about in previous
earnings call, have resulted in increase
of our call center NPS to 74 in quarter
4 2026 from 60 in quarter 1 2026.
Before I close, the current year marks
an important milestone in the journey of
ICICI Lombard as we enter into our 25th
year of operation.
We would like to take this opportunity
to express our heartfelt gratitude to
all our stake stakeholders who have been
truly who has truly supported us in our
journey so far and we look forward to
your continued trust, encouragement, and
support in the years ahead.
I will now request Gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for
quarter 4 and financial year 2026.
Thank you, Sanjeev, and good evening to
each one of you.
I will now give you a brief overview of
the financial performance of the
recently concluded quarter in the full
financial year.
We have uploaded the results
presentation on our website.
You can access it as we walk you through
the performance numbers.
With effect from October 1, 2024,
long-term products are accounted on a
1/N basis as mandated by the regulator
IRDAI.
Please refer our investor presentation
slide number 16 for
the further details on comparison of
financials on a on an N and 1/N basis.
It may be noted that all the numbers
that I've been speaking about are on a
1/N basis unless otherwise mentioned.
On combined ratio,
our combined ratio on an N basis for
FY26 was 102.4%
as against 102.6% in FY25.
Our combined ratio on a 1/N basis for
the current year was 103.4 as against
102.8%
in FY25.
Excluding the impact of wage code of
rupees 0.55 billion,
the combined ratio for FY26 stood at
102.1%
and 103.1%
on a N basis and 1/N basis,
respectively.
Our combined ratio on a N basis for
quarter four was 100.5
as against 102.1 in quarter four of
FY25.
Our combined ratio on a one by N basis
for quarter four current year was 101.2
as against 102.5 in quarter four of last
year.
On the investments, our investment
assets during the quarter rose to rupees
584.21 billion
as at March 31, 2026 up from rupees
582.96 billion as at December 31, 2025.
Our investment leverage net of borrowing
was at 3.48 times at March 31, 2026
and at 3.6 times as at December 31,
2025.
Investment income was at rupees 47.42
billion in FY26 as against rupees
42.5 billion in FY25.
On a quarterly basis, investment income
was at rupees 9.85 billion
in Q4 this year as against rupees 8.77
billion in Q4 last year.
During the quarter under review, the
company has recognized we have a policy
on impairment of
investment assets.
Uh basis that, the company has
recognized an impairment on its equity
portfolio investments of rupees
.49 billion in this quarter for FY26
versus a small write back that we had of
almost about three crores
uh that we had in quarter four of the
last financial year.
Driven by the prevailing market
correction.
Now, coming to profitability,
our profit before tax grew by 10.2% to
rupees 36.59 billion in FY26 as against
rupees 33.21 billion in FY25.
Excluding the impact of the wage code
that I referred earlier of rupees .55
billion,
the PBT grew by 11.8% to rupees 37.14
billion in FY26.
Our PBT grew by 7.5% to rupees 7.18
billion in Q4 FY26 as against rupees
6.68 billion in Q4 FY25.
On the profit after tax,
therefore consequently on a one by end
basis, the PAT grew by 10.5% to rupees
27.72 billion in FY26 as against rupees
25.08 billion in
FY25.
Again, excluding the impact of the wage
code,
the PAT on a one by end basis grew by
12.2% to rupees 28.14 billion in FY26.
On a end basis, PAT grew by 14.1% to
rupees 27.61 billion in FY26 as against
rupees
24.19 billion in FY25.
On a end basis, excluding the impact of
the wage code, the PAT grew by 15.9% to
rupees 28.03 billion in FY26.
Our PAT on a one by end basis grew by
7.3% to 5.47 billion in Q4
this year as against rupees 5.1 billion
in Q4 last year.
Same amount on a end basis, PAT grew by
15.6% to to rupees 5.39 billion in Q4
FY26 as against
4.66 billion in Q4 FY25.
Coming to return on average equity, our
ROE was
17.8% in FY26 as against 19.1% in FY25.
Excluding the impact of wage code of
rupees 0.55 billion, the ROE stood at
18.1%
for FY26.
ROE for uh quarter four current year was
at 13.3%.
As against 14.5% in Q4 FY25.
Coming to dividend,
the board of directors of the company
has proposed a final dividend of seven
per share for FY26.
This payment is however subject to
approval of shareholders in the ensuing
general annual general meeting of the
company.
The overall dividend for FY26 including
the above proposed final dividend is
rupees
13.5 per share.
Last year, the overall dividend was
rupees 12.5 per share.
On solvency, we continue to exhibit a
very healthy solvency ratio of
2.67 times at March 31st, 2026 as
against
2.69 at December 31, 2025.
Which continues to be higher than the
minimum regulatory requirement.
The solvency, of course, was impacted by
roughly about 14 basis points
as an outcome of the mark-to-market loss
position that we had on the equity book
as at March 31, 2026.
As I conclude, I would like to state
that we are aligned with our ethos of
driving profitable growth,
consistent and sustainable value
creation for all of our stakeholders,
while ensuring that the interest of
policyholders are at the forefront
at all times. I would like to thank you
all for attending this earnings call,
and we will now be happy to take
questions that you may have. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
We will now begin the question and
answer session.
Anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on their touch-tone
telephone.
If you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue, you may press star and
two.
Participants are requested to please use
handsets while asking a question.
Ladies and gentlemen, we will now wait
for a moment while the question queue
assembles.
Our first question comes from the line
of Supratim Datta from Jefferies. Please
go ahead.
Hello. Um
thanks a lot for the opportunity. My
first question is on the competitive
environment in the industry. Uh there
have been articles recently indicating
that competition in the commercial lines
have been fairly elevated. You indicated
that, you know, the motor lines come up
combined ratio remains elevated. So, if
you could give us an idea about, you
know, how competitive environment in the
different segments is panning out, that
would be helpful. And is there any
improvement you feel now
uh the UN guidelines kicking in? So,
that's my first question. The second
question, uh coming to the loss ratio
side. Uh
This year fourth quarter motor TP loss
ratio has been significantly lower than
what we have seen in the last uh years
in
fourth quarter motor TP loss ratio. So,
just wanted to understand, you know,
what has played out for this uh
significant improvement versus the run
rate that we have seen previously. And
why is the prop loss ratio negative? If
you could give some color on that.
Lastly, on IFRS matters, uh Gopal, you
know, wouldn't it be possible for you to
give us some understanding or clarity
regarding, you know, how your PAT under
IFRS would look versus the IGAAP PAT? Um
that would be very helpful. Thank you.
I'll take the second one first. Maybe I
can take the second and the third and
then maybe I can ask maybe Sanjeev can
respond the first one.
Um I think on the loss ratio, Supratim,
I think
this obviously comes to us every
quarter. And I think our response will
still remain the same as in to say that
one
you have to keep looking at motor as a
category as compared to one looking at
separately
motor own damage and third party. That's
one. Second,
I think we would continue to again
request all of you to keep looking at
numbers more on
uh fully year basis as compared to let's
say any given quarter.
And just to kind of refresh what we have
been telling the street is
I think the range that we are
comfortable on motor is between 65 to
67.
I think that is the range that we have
maintained and if you have seen for the
fully year current year, I think we
ended at roughly about 66.3%.
It's well within that range. And hence
to that extent, I think that's the range
that we would be kind of tracking pretty
closely.
Uh so, in that sense, there is nothing
that has kind of changed. Uh if you ask
us has has any of our reserving
philosophy undergone a change, the short
answer is no. And we continue to kind of
maintain prudence
uh in terms of maintaining our loss
reserves. So, hence
I think we have to keep looking at
numbers more on fully a basis as
compared to any given quarters.
So, that's one. Crop, I think again time
and again we have kind of talked about
it because
generally again just to kind of refresh,
most of the businesses in crop get
booked around quarter two and somewhere
around quarter three and maybe early
quarter four.
For those are typically the two seasons
that largely get exhibited. In our case,
we had predominantly a large exposure on
crop largely from one state. Of which a
large part of our premium was something
that had got kind of booked roughly
around quarter two of the year.
And as we have said, it obviously takes
time for the season to kind of play out
in terms of actual loss experiences.
And in any in any quarter when you see
that experience play out, then to that
extent obviously and they could
recollect even at the time of booking
the policies, we obviously follow a very
very conservative approach of providing
for almost 100% loss ratio at the time
of writing the risk. And as the actual
experiences play out, obviously to that
extent in case if we see some kind of a
positive change, then to that extent
that gets reflected again in the given
quarter and hence to that extent is why
possibly you are seeing that number in
line with the loss ratio outcomes for
quarter four. Here again, I would
continue to urge that you should again
look at the numbers more on a fully a
basis. On a fully a basis is pretty much
kind of range bound whether you look at
FY '25 or whether whether you look at FY
'26.
On India's, I think
in line with what we had also kind of
put out as a part of the opening
transcript, at this point of time
given the state at which the one if you
ask us is the now now that is now
there's a definitive
date in so far as transitioning to
India's is concerned. So, hence that's a
very very welcome step in so far as the
overall industry is concerned. I think
that's what rightfully so the regulator
has done it. In terms of uh,
our own transition, I think we do have,
uh, we have been working on a plan of
action in terms of getting our uh,
processes internally, uh, up and ready
so that we are able to kind of start
reporting, uh,
numbers to all of you, uh,
uh,
whenever we are kind of ready for it.
Um, at this point of time, I think we
will continue to kind of give, uh, in
line with what we have done even in the
past. We have been submitting pro forma
numbers
uh, for the last 2 years. So, we will
continue even for '26, '27 on a
quarterly basis in line with the
requirements. We will continue to submit
uh, India India's based results, uh, to
the regulator. And maybe we will come
back
to all of you at an appropriate time,
uh, and then we will possibly, uh, start
talking about more specifics in terms of
the impact that it does on both, uh, the
combined ratios and maybe the return on
equity objectives because those are the
two two things that the market obviously
kind of wants to hear from us. So, we
will come back on that. Uh, and maybe on
the first point, Sanjay,
>> also, you know, from the just to close
out the IFRS part, and we have always
said in the past also that, uh,
the year of adoption, there would be a
significant decline in combined ratio.
It can be in the range of 300 basis to,
you know, maybe, uh, 400 450 basis
points. But, look, that's only the
accounting part of it. Economic value
over a period of time, it is expected to
converge and have the
same, uh, you know,
value creation for the company as it
happens. So,
so, our stand pretty much remains same,
and yes, from next quarter one, we would
end up doing our submissions on that
count. Uh, with respect to the we spoke
about that
also when we were giving the overall
briefing for the
year that has gone by. Yes, it has
intensified on commercial line of
business. Uh, at the same time, the
capacity overall on the reinsurance side
was very high available, and we've been
able to see To extent is getting give
you
will this continue? My my own belief is
market forces will play out, but our own
understanding is when we see intensive
competition, the selection has to get
sharper
because it's
will be competing in the market. Answer
is yes,
but
what we've been able to write and what
we will write, we will be creating
differentiation. If you remember last
year even in
our quarter we had said that there was a
marginal loss of market share for us on
the fire side. Purely was on account of
the fact that
we will do what is comfortable and the
output is in some ways here to see.
These are all very exposure driven
products and you have to be cautious of
what you pick and what you do and we
continue to follow that.
There is no overarching worry. We are
very well placed as an institution in
terms of what practices we have to
counter any such measure that come up in
the market and overall insurance general
insurance in particular have seen
these kind of conduct at multiple levels
and we are well placed about it. On
motor also on a similar vein, yes, the
industry is being
stretched at multiple counts. The
combined ratio which I just spoke about
for the 9 months stated 128 clearly not
a workable one. We continue to pick and
choose and deliver
a result which is differentiated from
the market. It's purely led by on
multiple count distribution and
underwriting practices which
differentiate in own damage as well as
third party with briefly you know
Gopal spoke about.
Thank you.
Understood. Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you, Pradeep.
Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Prayesh Jain from Motilal Oswal. Please
go ahead.
Yeah, hi everyone.
Few questions from my side two questions
on my side. Firstly, if I
just wanted to take a view on your
solvency, which is like
uh very high at 2.7. How do you think
that you will
uh whether you because you've been
generating good profits over the past
few years and in fact from FY22 to FY25
and even now the solvency has been
increasing. So, how do you see you know
whether you can utilize the solvency
better in terms of paying out dividends
or in any other form uh to kind of
because
and unless the growth is really
exceptional, uh we I'm sure that we
wouldn't need that kind of excess
solvency on the balance sheet. That's
question number one. Second, Sanjeev,
you know, you've been talking about
motor TP price hike and
uh you know, we've discussed this in the
last call last few calls as well, but
given the trajectory on the motor TP
loss ratio that about 63.2 in FY25 and
63.8 this year for you, uh do you think
that uh you know, motor TP price hike
can
uh
come in?
Uh
and my last question is on on the health
insurance front. Uh uh Gopal, if you
could split up the loss ratios uh retail
and
Yeah. Yeah, so maybe yeah. Uh so uh so
Paresh,
uh so the first one I think
Um I think as a company, uh what we have
always maintained is uh
uh sufficient margins when it comes to
solvency because uh
Indi-
uh the Indian market is still on
solvency one regulation. I think of
course there is a road map
to maybe eventually transition to
risk-based capital, which again, as what
as what the regulator has rightfully
done on and do a similar thing even on
transition to risk-based capital as
well. So, obviously one will have to
wait and see how that plays out, but
till that point of out, but till that
point of
think the Indian market continues to be
guided by solvency one.
Uh which uh as I said, still mandates uh
capital off to be maintained basis the
gross exposures that you have as an
entity and hence to that extent we'll
have to be uh mindful of and prudent uh
in terms of the levels of solvency that
we carry as an institution. Um having
said that, I think uh
to your point on the last few years, I
think uh fair observation, but if you
see I think last couple of years in
specific, I think we have been
relatively uh lower uh when it comes
when it comes to growth. But that's
something that we have already seen a
clear positive uh reversal of trends
emerging for us.
And uh with the momentum that uh that we
have kind of seen, uh in all fairness,
one would obviously want to kind of make
sure that we are able to kind of get it
extended uh even as we head into FY27.
And the moment you will see as what you
have seen, uh let's say even uh uh in
the second half of this year, growth
kind of coming back. Uh so to that
extent, obviously one will uh look at uh
consuming some part of uh the solvency
that we have.
And three, our uh solvency is also
guided by obviously a mix of what is it
that we want to drive in terms of the
growth objective. And two, at the same
time make sure that we are kind of
appropriately kind of uh rewarding uh
the investors who have kind of obviously
placed faith in us. And in that context,
I think if you'd have seen historically,
we do have a board governed uh dividend
distribution policy in place.
Uh on an average, I think what we have
been able to kind of distribute uh is
roughly about uh 25% of our PAT. And
this year again, as what we had kind of
put out in the opening transcript, that
roughly about 13 and 1/2 rupees per
share for the full year, uh roughly
translates to almost about 25% of our
profit after tax. Uh so hence it's
obviously will be a continued
combination of both uh rewarding the
shareholders appropriately and at the
same time making sure that we are able
to use the capital for uh
growth. And the three and the third part
as I said we will obviously kind of keep
a watch on the transition to risk-based
capital. So that's one.
Uh to your point on the breakup for the
health the loss ratio numbers I think it
yeah thankfully this time the question
has come ahead of time so maybe we'll
answer it. Uh so I think Q4 of last year
this right now I'll give you the numbers
for quarter four employer employee book.
Uh the last last year Q4 the loss ratio
was
98% and this year that number is almost
the same at 98.1%.
On the retail indemnity book uh the loss
ratio for Q4 last year was 64.8
and this year quarter four the loss
ratio on the indemnity book is at 57.6.
Now the same year numbers on a full year
basis employer employee book
for last year has been at 97.2
and this year full year the employer
employee book loss ratio stands at about
91.9.
On the retail indemnity full year last
year was 67.9.
This year full year is at about 64.6. Uh
so just therefore doubt to kind of
submit again on the indemnity book I
think the range that we have spoken
about is between 65 to 70% and that's
what we have been we have been kind of
largely talking through even in the past
several quarters and broadly if you see
the experience that one has seen the
good part is I think one we have been
able to book a build a book uh which is
pretty much to our liking and it has
kind of played out both in terms of
growth in market share and also staying
within the loss ratio range. Uh so those
are the responses to the two questions
maybe on the motor third party So yes
I think possibly it's been almost five
years now since the
uh industry has
got a hike at the loss ratio at the
industry level as far as motor TP is
concerned is at around 85 and
thereabouts.
Uh Which is significantly you know
elevated where we are we have been able
to
if you see and Gopal briefly spoke about
it. We have to also reconfigure our
portfolio to get a line and write the
efficiency
which we've been able to reflect.
It does at times leads to a loss and
whenever we end up having discussions
whether individually or collectively
there's so much of you know questioning
as to why has the market share gone down
gone up? That is what it takes to
reconfigure.
We've also recalibrated our practice in
terms of ground surveillance and doing
what is required to avoid fraud which
probably we would easily say is among
the lowest in the industry. There's no
way we can claim to eliminate it. So
there are multiple factors that go about
it. We remain desirous of the fact that
yes the TP height for the industry is
overdue and
sooner than later that should play out.
But
we can only control what is in in our
hand. This one definitely is not and in
line with that we continue to forge
our own understanding and deliberation
to penetrate market at multiple counts
and make it work for us as a company and
from an industry standpoint sooner than
later we do hope the relief comes
through.
Thank you. Thank you so much. Thank you.
Fresh.
Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Sanket Goda from Avendus Spark. Please
go ahead.
Yeah, thank you. Thank you for the
opportunity.
So my my my first question is is that
last year we we kind of lost market
share in commercial lines
and and given given the market is soft
as you highlighted,
is it fair to say that
we we will claw back kind of the market
share in the soft market or we will
remain as cautious as we were last time.
And and and and and in in these lines,
just wanted to understand given given
the soft market growth outlook,
given given
your second half growth is 16% and maybe
crop being a new tendering
tendering
year,
how do you see growth of the 16% to
continue for the next year
and any any color if you can give on the
those lines will be very useful. That's
my first question. Maybe maybe I'll ask
another one later. Okay. So no Sanket, I
think uh
last year
I'm saying when you're saying last year
it's the year before the one which you
just given the result of the financial
25, we were we didn't lose market share,
we had gained by 0.1. We had a quarter
here and there we missed but overall we
had gained.
We are talking about a market share
which is in the range of 13.7
which was the year before last. This
year we have closed by 0.8, 0.7. This is
0.1 lower
and it's driven through multiple
configuration. When we meet up
personally I'm more than happy to Sanket
run through that.
These are the that kind of a share that
we draw these fluctuations to ensure
that we select right can happen but
the commercial practice that we have is
very unique in the industry and it's not
driven by what business we are able to
write. It's about how we are able to
even manage claims.
There's a significant contribution on
large corporates to mid and to small.
Honestly speaking from an entity
standpoint we have been we have done a
much more
you know decent job on the large
corporate side and over last two to
three years which we have been briefing
to you, it's been a more distribution
led growth and we have been able to
diversify our
portfolio in a in a significant manner.
We do we do believe that
we are we have a very significant edge
in the overall practice and we will be
able to
uh have a you know
a reasonable presence as far as
commercial is concerned. I don't want to
jump the gun to say uh where the market
share will be, but we will be a very
relevant player and it's not uh easy to
see us losing foothold on that on an
overarching basis.
Crop coming into play, we will
uh and yes, the market opens up
significantly. We are still awaiting the
details in terms of on what contours
this market will open as and when those
guidelines come in,
uh we will be able to comment as to what
it is.
But we've always maintained our stand
that crop will be purely on selection
basis of what we feel is appropriate
rather than a targeted segment where we
say "Humko itna karna hi hai." You know,
that's not the way we look at it. Uh do
we want to participate? It's a bold yes.
Do we want to, you know, chase it? The
answer is no. Uh
We we are very well placed overall the
to and we are excited actually in terms
of the opportunity that will present
itself. Uh our current crop number
reserve is what was there year before
last to this year has virtually halved
and
uh there is some play available for us
to make it count in this year.
Yeah. Understood.
Yeah.
Yeah. Sorry.
Oh, sorry. You're saying something. Go
ahead. Please go ahead.
>> Uh no, no, no, no, no, the the sorry
sorry something like When I meant uh
April last year, you lost market share
in commercial lines because you believed
the market was too soft. And and if
you're assuming it is too soft again, uh
maybe maybe fully you caught it up, but
but but given April is very strong in
the renewal for for
uh fire, whether whether
whether uh whether whether it will have
any implication in one Q growth or or
April growth which is which is uh
significantly very big. And and lastly
Uh yeah, yeah, something. Yeah, go
ahead. You ask me.
>> lastly on crop, crop just just wanted to
add is that uh
whether whether you confined till till
last 3 years to to one state. Maybe I
don't know what final controls will be
but it is fair to say that you you will
be expanding beyond a particular state
in in in the current year or not.
Broadly broadly that's that's way you
are strategically thinking in those
lines or not is the point I wanted to
check. Yeah, yeah, you know you know so
so one state worked out because it was a
line of what you wanted to do. It is not
a plan that will come due to be a one
state person. We will go
wherever it makes
you know
commercial sense and we believe that it
is appropriate and crop obviously can
play out the way it is. We are still
awaiting structure. So there is there is
we are open to
whatever that comes up our way to be
very honest on that point. And on the
commercial part in terms of
what you are saying
Look, the growth of the industry itself
will get impacted and we are we are such
we are an offshoot of that. So
we can do better, we can do worse
depending on how it pans out
but overall if you remember in H1
we had a
much bigger loss vis-a-vis what happened
in H2. So
we also done what is required. So what
cannot get
you know what cannot be acquired through
large corporate we have played out in
distribution has taken its own play but
we are very well in I mean so we should
be fine on the commercial part also
overall as an entity.
Understood. So from growth point of view
given
I am sorry to interrupt. We request you
to please No, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no,
It would be probably single digit.
It's It's Sorry, Sanjeev, just to
squeeze in. I I got asking that second
half our growth was 16% globally in weak
in first half. So, this 16% growth run
rate uh you expect to continue largely
for FY27?
There is There is so much happening all
around that
uh
how do you project that? But yes, Gopal
mentioned that very briefly. We are very
confident of moving into the quarter one
and quarter two on a positive note
overall. As things stand. Yes, we But
how does the industry play out overall?
We will have to watch at that. Uh
we also presume that the the the
tailwinds which got cleared on account
of GST cut which led to a very robust
quarter four
would continue to play out. Definitely
will be well placed for a growth. We We
are excited with that opportunity, but
we'll have to wait in terms of how the
market plays out.
Yeah. Thank you. Okay. Yeah, thanks.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Nitesh from Investec. Please go ahead.
Thanks for the opportunity, sir. So, my
question is on motor. So, in motor in H1
we grew lesser than the market and in H2
we grew faster than the market. So, what
drove that and what is the outlook of
our growth vis-a-vis industry growth in
FY27
on in the motor segment?
Yeah, okay. So, Nitesh, I think
yes, H2 was better. There was also
a significant play that came out on
account of new sales
for the country doing better and there
is no denying in You know, there's
nothing which we can say
that we tend to do better when new sales
are
very high and we have seen that new grew
at almost 18.8%
for us vis-a-vis 13.4 on the old side.
So,
on the outlook of financial year 2027
um
we'll have to see. We do expect a higher
single digit growth at the industry
level and if that happens, it would be
again
good for us. And other thing which
worked out last year was the growth of
two-wheeler by my when I was talking I
said that it was a decadal high in terms
of the overall growth that happened. We
in for last three, four years we've been
saying that we have not beaten the
pre-COVID number on two-wheeler. That
itself is again a big plus overall on
the motor side. I think the only thing
there I'll just add to this just to what
Sanjeev was saying. I think one of the
thing initiatives that we have been also
been speaking in our earlier calls
is our relentless focus on improving
retentions.
Uh
and we'll be very again happy to kind of
indicate that for the full year
I think at an aggregate let's say
company level, a large part of which
will be predominantly let's say retail
business lines. I think we have seen an
improvement in our overall retention
numbers go up by almost about 5
percentage points.
Uh so hence that is something that we
will continue to stay focused on even as
we head into FY27. That will be an
important lever
uh that we would obviously kind of
work on uh beyond of course the point
that Sanjeev made in so far as new
vehicle sales is concerned.
Yeah. So the growth growth acceleration
that we have seen is a function of
growth new vehicle sales going up. New
as well as Uh the competition intensity
reducing and we gaining market share on
a like-to-like basis.
Uh so yeah, so new and old and I think
it did sometime in quarter one last year
that we had as a company extensively
worked on the retention part. A lot of
work was done on multiple counts
by us.
And that's what Gopal is referring to
when he's saying that we had a delta of
a higher retention of our customers.
Sure. So and that's so so
so
should we Q3 and Q4 trend to play out
next year also that we will grow faster
than the industry or
Uh
I think I think let me put it this way.
We will we are well placed overall, but
there are multiple factors. See, I mean
if there is a there is a challenge on
the energy if the
if the Indian mentality moves into the
saving part of it rather than spending,
the motor sales auto sales which
probably all of you are well aware of it
actually ends up getting really muted.
We'll have to see how that part comes
in.
But, we would say that
the momentum on quarter three to quarter
four and so effectively in quarter one
should play out.
I would say yes, we are going with a
very positive mindset at this point of
time.
Sure, sir.
That's it from my side.
Thanks. Thanks. Thanks very much.
Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Avinash Singh with MK Global. Please go
ahead.
Yeah, hi.
Thanks for the opportunity. Good
evening. A couple of questions. The
first one a bit I would say if you can
clarify my understanding, this
49 crore kind of charge that you have
taken for diminishing in value of
investment
provisions in this quarter. Is it
largely driven by the equity for market
fall or bond or kind of
both? So, that's one. And second, in
motor TP, of course, you have explained
a lot of things.
Now, my question is that okay, we have
not seen a sort of a price hike. But,
what I changed for you that you have
kind of accelerated your growth in CV
segment. Now, typically from whatever we
hear, it is a CV by and large where the
price revision is required and it's not
so profitable. But, in Q4,
it seems that you have gone
a lot higher in terms of, you know,
that CV. So, what had changed there?
What kind of a strategy is there? And
for the full year, around 780 crores of
motor third party reserves will be
there.
Is that number I'm seeing correctly?
Thanks.
The last one is
So, maybe I can take the last one.
So, Avinash, again again we will keep
saying
you should keep looking at the loss
ratio range that we have spoken about
for motor as a category, which is
between 65 to 67.
An absolute amount of
reserve number that you spoke about,
honestly
in our sense is something that would not
necessarily be a right metric to kind of
track. A better metric will be to keep
looking at the loss ratio outcome, which
is the range that we have kind of spoken
about between 65 to 67. But, the good
part is I think I think what has worked
for us, I think is I think we have seen
a clear rebound of growth.
And at the same time we have been able
to maintain the loss ratio expectations
that we have set out. So, hence that
extent I think is where we have been
able to deliver both on growth as well
as in so far as the loss outcomes. And
that's something that we are very very
happy with and we are very very positive
when we kind of head into FY '27. And as
I said in response to the earlier
question, is there any change in the
thought process of any of our reserving
philosophies or reserving processes?
Absolutely no.
We continue to maintain prudence. We
continue to maintain
margins for any levels of uncertainty
that we see in any of the book. And more
so in the context of motor third party,
which has got a long tail
a long tail periods of loss development.
So, hence to that extent that's in
response to the point on motor third
party.
To your first point
or to to the on the first question with
respect to the 49 crore diminution in
the value of investments, I think this
is what I kind of
mentioned even as a part of the opening
transcript. We have a policy on
impairment of investments that we kind
of have in the context of
equity investment specifically and
consequent to what we have seen
the market conditions getting exhibited
in quarter four of this year. We have
obviously evaluated stocks that we hold.
And this is the policy that we have. We
have done an impairment of about 49
crores. All of this 49 crores is in with
respect to the policy on diminution in
the value of equity investments.
Yeah, okay. So now on the
CV growth, I think you're absolutely
right.
It's done better. But there are, you
know, multiple moving parts. I don't
want to get into details. We can do it
probably when we meet up Avinash
and talk about it. We've done better,
but the overall contribution of CV to
the book has still been range bound at
22%. Uh,
you see multiple, you know, things. And
there's one more aspect that the cost of
equation that comes into play. And if we
see moderation, we see an opportunity.
We are also scanning the market, adding
new vectors. And something looks viable,
we end up doing it. We've also created a
significant edge vis-a-vis the market
through a fleet management system which
we are working for last almost,
you know, 18 to 24 months. And that has
also started giving us some bit of an
advantage as to what we can do in
commercial vehicles.
It's It's Overall, I think it's still
come range bound.
And we do believe that the overall
growth in CV market also for S2 was at a
reasonable level which we have given in
the numbers of the details which also
again presented us with an opportunity
to do what is required. Uh,
overall our practice that if you see
where ICICI Lombard is, certainly
private car and two-wheeler is
uh, are you know, our strength. But CV
we continue to
exhibit a lot more intensity, but the
outcome used to be moderate
for us. And for last
couple of quarters, it's come into play
and I sincerely hope that they'll have a
similar trend going forward next year.
Or this year, rather.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Nishchint Chawathe from Kotak. Please go
ahead.
Hi, uh, this is slightly open-ended, uh,
uh,
the regulator is, uh, you know, looking
at, uh,
uh, you know, newer set of, uh,
guidelines or commissions, uh, you know,
probably capping commissions or
deferring them. Uh, you know, assuming
that, you know, this kind of leads to
some amount of tightening. How do you
see this impact on the industry and for
yourself? Uh, Nishchint, I think we've
always maintained, you know,
uh, an an environment with, uh, where
the regulator enforces it. In the past
also, we have said that there are quite
a few players who have sought
dispensation or have not followed the
guideline, and that does not augur well.
Any tightening on a uniform, which is
across the industry, uh, would place
ICICI Lombard, uh, at a significant
advantage, uh,
uh, because we've remained within the
limits of expense of management, and,
uh, if others fall in place, uh, we can
only see
uh, better time ahead for us as an
industry. The The only thing that
remains is, uh, it should be practiced,
uh, across the industry at a uniform
basis on a uniform basis.
And so, if anything is
kind,
uh, if it comes out, uh, we always also
mention the fact that we believe the
expense of management should be on a
single slab basis, uh, so that there is
clarity of execution, and let the market
forces decide as to what, uh, works for
each one of them in every single
business line.
So, so what is the latest in terms of,
uh, you know, regulatory engagement on
EOM? Is there any revision expected
around the corner along with this,
separately?
We can we can only say that whatever is
accessed by each one of you is what we
access and the we await for what the
regulator has in mind. We don't want to
do any second-guessing, but
any tightening on account of that would
be welcomed by us because it puts the
industry in
good path with respect to policy holder
and also for us as an institution.
Got it. Got it. Thank you very much and
all the best.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we will take that as the last question
for today.
I would now like to hand the conference
over to Mr. Sanjeev Mantri for closing
comments.
Over to you, sir.
Thank you so much for joining in.
We look forward to the new financial
with renewed hope. We have definitely as
a team
been excited as to how we've been able
to close H2 over H1 and more so Q4 over
the rest of it.
We are positive in terms of how things
can work out for general insurance
industry at large and with the reforms
that the regulator has put in place,
but at the same time
we hope that
the world moves to a in a in a much
more, you know, peaceful manner in times
to come. So, thank you so much and all
the best to each one of you for joining
in. Thank you so much. Thank you.
Thank you.
On behalf of ICICI Lombard General
Insurance Company Limited, that
concludes this conference.
Thank you all for joining us. You may
now disconnect your lines.